JON STALEY

London
Email: jmstaley@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

A resourceful, dedicated and enthusiastic software developer with significant experience of a wide range of computer applications and programming languages underpinned by strong client-facing skills and a degree in Internet Engineering. Quick to grasp new ideas, concepts and technologies, and keen to continue to expand upon knowledge and expertise. Demonstrates the organisation and motivation required to meet demanding targets, and thrives in highly pressurised and challenging working environments. Combines a professional and hard-working approach with excellent interpersonal and team-working skills and can communicate confidently at all levels.

OBJECTIVE

Now looking for a new and challenging position, one which will make best use of existing skills and experience and provide opportunity for further responsibility and professional development.

CAREER SUMMARY

2015-date Developer, Founders Factory, London

Worked alongside product managers to design and build early stage technology for startups. Working mainly on the backend and infrastructure required to get projects running quickly, both more traditional REST api work with Flask and an AWS lambda implemented api. Helping other developers in other teams where required, sharing expertise and writing code.

2014-2015 Senior Developer, mumoActive, London

Employed to design and build the restful api backend using Django for the Type-1 diabetes tracker and helping out in all parts of the development. Responsibilities included helping to maintain the iOS application, helping to build a patient and clinic dashboard using Angularjs, building the Android version of the application and implementing Ansible playbooks for server automation

2012-2014 Senior Developer, FundingOptions, London

Employed to help build and maintain the backend sevices using python and pyramid, add features as required. In my role there I designed and implemented the restful api for running the services, introduced Ansible to automate deployments, helped to mentor junior developers and helping to interview new staff.

2011-2012 Software Developer, Newman Online, London

Employed to help maintain and improve the multi-site ticketing system, primarily used by cinemas. Responsibilities include designing and implementing new features from start to finish, improving the current systems responsiveness, maintaining the continuous integration system, dealing with bugs raised by customers and providing out of hours support.

Projects:

- Designing and implementing a Direct Debit payment system alongside another member of the team.
- Implementing a High Availability web cluster with Heartbeat to provide redundancy for a clients website sales.
- Designing and implementing a product combo sales solution.

2010-2011 Software Consultant, TUI UK, Luton

Employed on a years contract to help maintain and improve the Carmen Pairing and Rostering software, working in a small team inside of the Airline IT department. Responsibilities included working closely with the planners to fix bugs and identify ways in which the system could be improved and new features implemented. Developing solutions using Python and the proprietary Rave language. Helping to improve the bug reporting process to enable effective triage and fixing of issues.

Working alongside other team members to help improve existing projects outside of Carmen, including a crew web application.

2005-2009 Software Developer, Jamkit, London

- Employed initially in a junior post and progressing quickly to a software development role of increasing responsibility
- Working effectively within a small and integrated team to provide web solutions, front-end and back-end support for a range of non-profit, commercial and public sector clients
- Developing solutions using Python and a custom-built CMS running on the Zope application server, utilising DTML and ZPT templating languages
- Using agile methodologies such as Continuous Integration, pair programming and Test Driven Development
- Undertaking a range of support and basic server administration duties to ensure the efficient delivery of the company's services
- Working successfully to briefs, including:
 - Building an internal appraisal system for the Natural History Museum
 - Developing new website functionality for Cambridge International Examinations, supporting their existing code
 - Improving functionality for the CMS, including developing a Twitter tool, RSS feed tool and a range of other components

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

B Eng: Internet Engineering

<u>Final Year Modules</u>: Software Engineering, Computer & Communication Networks, Networked Information, Interactive Computer Graphics, Middleware

Final Year Project: Web-based Client Email System

OTHER INTERESTS

Currently have an account on github (http://github.com/jmstaley) containing current projects and scripts that I've written.

REFERENCES ARE AVAILABLE ON REQUEST